hostbillapp.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy | HostBill | Billing & Automation Software for WebHosts

At HostBill we appreciate the trust that our customers give us by providing their personal information. We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of all personal information and we always use that personal information in a way that is fair and worthy of that trust. We undertake all reasonable steps to protect your information from misuse and keep it secure. 

The Privacy Policy document specifies what kind of information HostBill collects from the website users and explains how this information can be used. Please read the following statement to learn more about our Privacy Policy. 

#### 1\. Data Collector

The controller of your personal data is HostBill Krzysztof Pająk; post address: Trembeckieg 11A/205 street, 35-234 Rzeszow; VAT No. PL 8133336364; Company No. #180579931. If we mention HostBill in this document, we mean Krzysztof Pająk and his business activity. 

#### 2\. Personally Identifiable Information

“Personally identifiable information” is information that we can use to identify you as an individual. Personally identifiable information include your name, address, telephone number and anyother information that is connected with you personally. It is also known as “personal data”. 

HostBill collects personally identifiable information only if the customer supplies it voluntarily during the order process on our website or when getting in touch with us using contact form or subscribing to our newsletter. 

All personal data is kept in our database and will not be shared with or sold to any third parties, with the exception of financial institutions in cases where identity theft or fraud is suspected and other state or international institutions when it is prescribed by law. 

#### 3\. Lawfulness of processing

Personally identifiable information is processed by HostBill only for regular business purposes: to deliver products and services, to administrate customer accounts and provide customer support. With your consent, it might be also used for direct marketing purposes.

If you want to buy our products or services, we need your name, surname and, if you have one, company name and VAT number. It is also necessary that you provide us your exact address (street, apartment number, city, province, country), email and telephone address, so that we can contact with you and deliver ordered products. In case you need support, we also keep your login password and the IP address. Processing of those data is necessary for the performance of a contract in which you are a party or in order to undertake steps at your request prior to concluding a contract and for compliance with a legal obligation.

On the other hand, your name and surname, company name, VAT number and address will be used to issue an invoice. It is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation.

In order to verify your identity you will be asked to provide us with a scan of your ID card or bill. Neither those documents nor information they present will be collected in any filing system, but delated immediately after verification. Processing of those data is necessary for the purposes of preventing fraud and ensuring IT security.

If you subscribed to our newsletter, we hold your email address, name and company name. This mailing list is used for sending updates and the latest announcements regarding HostBill, new products, security updates and other information that may be of interest to our customers. This is why we need your consent to add your to our mailing list. If you don’t want to receive these messages any more, you can opt out by following the instructions in the message. It needs to be stressed that consent to receive our newsletter is not a necessary condition of using our products or services.

If you correspond with us by email, we also may retain your email address and any personal details included in the message that are necessary to deal with your request. Your email addresses is not automatically subscribed to our mailing list. In case you want to keep up with our offer, you should subscribe to our newsletter and agree to processing your personal data in direct marketing purposes. 

#### 4\. Use of Cookies

Cookies are pieces of data stored on your hard drive concerning a current or previous web session. Cookies are commonly used to recognize your computer in the future. We may use a cookie to record previously established interests and preferences (via data submitted to us) to enhance your experience with our website and to better understand how people use our website. The cookie is client-side so while using cookies your privacy is not in any way compromised. You may deactivate cookies in your web browser, or reject the creation of cookies according to your personal preferences. If you do so, our website functionality may be compromised and certain services may not be available. 

#### 5\. IP Address Information

For every website visit we record which pages users visited and track the IP address that was used to access the website. An IP address is a unique identifier assigned to you by your Internet provider when you connect to the Internet. Your IP address may differ each time you connect to the Internet or be permanently assigned to you, depending on your private arrangements. IP addresses are not linked to any kind of personally identifiable information. We use these addresses to track your movements, analyze broad trends such a geographical location, and by such means improve our quality of service. 

We may also collect the information about the browser types and browser versions our visitors use. This information is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual user. The information is only used to identify trends and our users preferences. We may from time to time share information gathered this way with our partners. 

#### 6\. Storage limitation

We keep your data in a form which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than it is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed (correct performance of the contract; compliance with a legal obligation; direct marketing). After this time period, the data is stored solely for the purpose of securing legal claims. 

#### 7\. Your rights

Under data protection law, as the subject of such data, you have right to: 

  * access to your personal data;
  * rectification of inaccurate personal data;
  * erasure of personal data (‘right to be forgotten’);
  * restrict processing;
  * object to processing;
  * receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or transmit those data to another controller (right to data portability);
  * complain to a supervisory authority; and
  * the right to withdraw consent to processing.

You have the right to check whether or not we process your personal data and, when if we process such data, you are entitled to obtain access to the personal data and additional information including details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we can provide you with a copy of your personal data. The first copy provided is free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. Please remember you can get an access to your personal data by logging into your account on our website.

Moreover you have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed. Remember you can also modify your personal data on your own when logged into your account on our website.

Under some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. You ‘will not be forgotten’ when processing of your personal data is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data if you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is your consent or necessity for the performance of the contract and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of other people.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection law, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint to a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by contacting us (by using the contact form on our website). 

#### 9\. Confidentiality and Security Safeguards

HostBill undertakes all reasonable precautions to protect personally identifiable information against loss, misuse or unauthorized access. All personal information is maintained in a secure environment and only accessible by the authorized personnel under a duty of confidentiality. 

#### 10\. External Links

The hostbillapp.com website, blog, wiki and the users’ forum may contain various links to external websites. These links may be included to point the reader to other possibly relevant resources. External links do not imply endorsement by HostBill of the associated websites or the information, products or services contained therein. HostBill is not in control and is not responsible under any circumstances for the content and/or privacy practices of externally referenced websites. 

#### 11\. Changes in Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy may change occasionally. We will post the changes on this page. If the changes are significant, we may also choose to email all our registered users with the new details. Where required by the law provisions, we shall obtain your consent to make these changes. 

##### Last updated: 2018-03-29
